Scrapbooks of Loring Campbell, 1924-1960(bulk 1924-1945)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Scrapbooks of Loring Campbell, 1916-1979
MS 233
Campbell, Loring, 1905-1979
The Scrapbooks of Loring Campbell is comprised of 14 scrapbooks which contain newspaper clippings, brochures, programs, posters, correspondence, and memorabilia recounting Loring Campbell’s career as a performer.
3.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://www.library.arizona.edu/speccoll
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Loring Campbell was an American magician, ventriloquist, and humorist on the Chautauqua and lyceum circuits. He began his career in 1920 in a minstrel show as "Cambello the Clown Magician" and also performed a Chinese act before finding vaudeville success with his trademark suave stage persona as "The Great Alexander" and later, simply Loring Campbell. He performed in an estimated 1,500 shows before retiring in 1955.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 2 series
Series I: Biographical
Series II: Scrapbooks
Scope and Content Note
Fourteen scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, brochures, programs, posters, correspondence, and memorabilia from 1924-1960. The material regards Loring Campbell's public appearances in the southern and mid-western United States.
American Vaudeville Museum collection, MS 421.
Access Terms
Campbell, Loring, 1905--Archives.
Ventriloquists--United States.
Magicians--Biography--Sources.
Chautauquas.
Vaudeville.
Entertainers--United States.
Container List
- Biographical.
  - Loring Campbell. No date (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Other performers. No date (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Scrapbooks.
  - Scrapbook, 1926-1944. (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1930-1959. (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1924-1958. (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1926-1959. (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1939. (Box 3, Volume 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1925-1937. (Box 3, Volume 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1934-1935. (Box 4, Volume 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1938. (Box 4, Volume 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1941-1942. (Box 4, Volume 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1943. (Box 5, Volume 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1931-1938. (Box 5, Volume 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1943. (Box 6, Volume 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1940. (Box 6, Volume 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1943. (Box 7, Volume 14)